<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2020">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Eneo Tecnología S.L. |">
]>

<chapter>
	<title>Advanced</title>
	<para>In this chapter we will show some advanced settings and tools for Redborder configuration and administration.</para>
	<section>
		<title>Architecture</title>
		<para>Redborder has an open source based architecture, using technologies like Snort, Kafka or Logstash.</para>
		<para>All these technologies are orquested by Zookeeper and Chef, so it is important to have those services running for the good functioning of Redborder.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img001.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Architecture of Redborder</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Operations</title>
		<para>There are some important operations that must be executed in order to do advanced settings in Redborder.</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="circle">
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">motd</emphasis>: Motd shows general info about node and cluster</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img002.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Motd: output</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_get_managers.rb</emphasis>: Shows information about nodes on the cluster</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img003.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_get_managers.rb: output</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_get_services.sh</emphasis>: Get all the services status on the node. Used with option all shows information for all nodes. If optional the service is added too, only the status of this service is shown</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img004.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_get_services.sh: output</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_set_service.rb</emphasis>: Allows to enable or disable a service.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img005.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_set_service.rb: usage</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_service</emphasis>: Allows to work with a service. It can start, stop and restart services. Can be used with services such as postgresql, riak, hadoop, zookeeper, druid, kafka, chef and more.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img006.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_service: usage</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_set_topics.rb</emphasis>: Assign the destination of the topic, which can be samza or realtime. Corresponding services need to be started to keep the correct working of the redborder platform.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img007.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_set_topics.rb: usage</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_cluster_configure.rb</emphasis>: Get all services status for all nodes. Allows to change the configuration for the whole cluster.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img008.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_cluster_configure.rb: usage</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_manager_ssh.sh</emphasis>: This command is used to move or execute another command on other node.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img009.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_manager_ssh.sh: usage</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_manager_scp.sh</emphasis>: This script is used to copy a file from the manager where is being launched to all other nodes or a list of nodes.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img010.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_manager_scp.sh: usage</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_cluster_reboot.sh</emphasis>: Order the reboot for all cluster nodes.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img011.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_cluster_reboot.sh: usage</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_cluster_update.sh</emphasis>: It is used to upgrade the manager to a new released version.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img012.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_cluster_update: usage</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_get_tasks.rb</emphasis>: Gets information about indexing service.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img013.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_get_tasks.rb: usage</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">rb_wakeup_chef</emphasis>: Starts the chef-client in all the nodes.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img014.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>rb_wakeup_chef: usage</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>					
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Redborder technologies</title>
		<para>In this section we will explain the <emphasis role="bold">main technologies</emphasis> Redborder uses to manage and use all data it is provided.</para>
		<para>All main technologies used in Redborder are open source, which allows period updates and more quality.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Siddhi</title>
				<para>Siddhi is an <emphasis role="bold">open source Complex Event Processor</emphasis> that Redborder uses in vault module to apply rules to incoming events. It allows us to create rules that can alert us from any kind of behaviour reflected in the events.</para>
				<para>Siddhi is used in Redborder to make it able to raise alarm when a determinate situation is present in the network.</para>
				<para>Siddhi uses an SQL sentence structure, so it is possible to edit all rules included in Redborder by default.</para>
				<para>It is necessary to have certain level of knowledge about Siddhi to create useful rules.</para>
				<para>It is necessary to <emphasis role="bold">activate the correlation engine</emphasis>. This will use more machine resources, so it is necessary to be sure that the system has enought RAM memory.</para>
				<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img015.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Siddhi rules available in the manager correlation engine</para>
							</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Snort</title>
				<para>Snort is an <emphasis role="bold">open source network intrusion prevention system</emphasis> that process and analyzes real time traffic.</para>
				<para>Redborder uses Snort in intrussion module to configure multiple rule policies, as well as store and analyze the alerts generated. </para>
				<para>Snort system is based in rules, which are partially provided by the community.</para>
				<para>It is possible to update the rules manually, so it ensures that, with the lastest set of Snort rules, the traffic is being analyzed and monitorized.</para>
				<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img016.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Table of IPS events</para>
							</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Hadoop</title>
				<para>Hadoop is an open source <emphasis role="bold">distributed processing framework</emphasis> that manages data processing and storage for big data applications running in clustered systems.</para>
				<para>It's used by Redborder to provide real time traffic analysis of Big Data.</para>
				<para>Also, Hadoop is not enabled by default in a Redborder manager, because of its requirements of resources. It is very important to have strong resources to run Redborder using Hadoop, at least 64Gb RAM.</para>
				<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img017.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Hadoop for RAW Storage</para>
							</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Radius</title>
				<para>Remote Authentication Dial-In User Service (RADIUS) is a <emphasis role="bold">networking protocol</emphasis>, operating on port 1812, that provides centralized Authentication, Authorization, and Accounting (AAA or Triple A) management for users who connect and use a network service. The RadiusProcessor class belongs to the rb-Samza-bi module.</para>
				<para>RADIUS is a <emphasis role="bold">client/server protocol</emphasis> that runs in the application layer, and can use either TCP or UDP as transport. Network access servers, the gateways that control access to a network, usually contain a RADIUS client component that communicates with the RADIUS server. RADIUS is often the back-end of choice for 802.1X authentication as well.</para>
				<para>In a redborder manager, by activating the advanced options in General Settings, it is possible to access a section called Radius Accounting and Radius Proxy Authentication.</para>
				<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="200" fileref="images/ch20_img018.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>General Settings: Radius Accounting and Radius Proxy Authentication section</para>
							</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<section>
					<title>Radius authentication server</title>
					<para>This section allows to activate a Radius authentication server. The user must indicate the Host IP and password.</para>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Add a Radius Accounting server:</emphasis> It is possible to add a new Radius Server by clicking on the <emphasis role="bold">+Add</emphasis> tab, then enter the shared IP and password. Click Update to save the changes made.</para>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Delete a Radius Accounting server:</emphasis> Click on the Delete icon next to the Radius server information to discard it.</para>
					<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch20_img019.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>General Settings: Radius Accounting</para>
							</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Radius Proxy Authentication</title>
					<para>This section allows you to activate a Radius authentication proxy server. The user must indicate the IP of the source Host, the IP of the destination Host and the respective passwords.</para>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Add a Radius authentication proxy server:</emphasis> It is possible to add a new Radius Proxy Server by clicking on the <emphasis role="bold">+Add</emphasis> tab, then enter the IP of the source Host, the IP of the destination Host and the respective passwords. Click Update to save the changes made.</para>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Delete a Radius authentication proxy server:</emphasis> Click on the Delete icon next to the proxy server information to discard it.</para>
					<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch20_img020.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>General Settings: Radius Proxy Authentication</para>
							</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Bulkstats</title>
					<para>Bulk statistics are <emphasis role="bold">statistics that are collected in a group or scheme</emphasis>, for example, system statistics, port statistics, or Radius statistics.</para>
					<para>It's possible to display Bulkstats information in the redBorder manager, for this it is necessary to configure the client part in the Cisco device to activate the sending of information to the manager via ftp.</para>
					<para>Once this is done, we can view all the information regarding Bulkstats in the redBorder manager by accessing its corresponding tab and selecting the desired fields within the Monitor module.</para>
					<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img021.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Monitor Module: Bulkstats fields</para>
							</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<para>But... <emphasis role="bold">How to define a custom bulkstat monitor?</emphasis></para>
					<para>To define custom Bulkstats monitor crafted specifically for a Bulkstats schema, it necessary that the user have a bulkstats schema in their network device. Once having this requirement,  then navigate to the <emphasis role="bold">Monitor Categories</emphasis> view.</para> 
					<para>It's located in: <emphasis role="bold">Tools -> Monitor Categories</emphasis>.</para> 
					<para>Before proceding to uploading it, the user must save the schema into a plan text file and give it a name for example: <emphasis role="bold">Bulkstats-Schema.txt</emphasis>.</para>
					<para>The file created should be a <emphasis role="bold">plain txt file</emphasis> and must contain the bulkstats schema that is define in the network device. Normaly the bulkstats schemas looks like this:</para>
					<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img022.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Bulkstats schemas: Plain txt file</para>
							</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<para>Then click on <emphasis role="bold">New Monitor Category</emphasis> button and a modal will be displayed:</para>
					<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img023.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>New Monitor Category: Modal displayed</para>
							</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<para>Inside the new monitor category formulary select Bulkstats under the Technology list. This will display the new option to put your bulkstats schema file that define the user configuration.</para>
					<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="250" fileref="images/ch20_img024.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>New Monitor Category: Technolgy selection</para>
							</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<para>To assign the new monitor category to a device sensor, it's necessary to create a device monitor if the user don't have one yet from Sensor Tree view.</para>
					<para>Click on the <emphasis role="bold">sensor menu</emphasis> and then click on <emphasis role="bold">Monitors</emphasis>.</para>
					<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img025.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Sensors menu: Monitors</para>
							</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<para>Then click on the category <emphasis role="bold">+ Add Monitor</emphasis></para>
					<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img026.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Monitors for Device: Add Monitor category</para>
							</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<para>Once this is done, the user must click on the <emphasis role="bold">+ Add</emphasis> button to add the monitor category described above.</para>
					<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img027.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Monitors for Device: Add Monitors modal displayed</para>
							</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<para>Once added the monitor to the sensor, It would diplay the destination where need to configure the device to send.</para>
					<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch20_img028.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Monitors for Device: Destination path</para>
							</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<para>The url corresponds to the destination path. It is necessary to configure sftp protocol in the device network to send the information regarding the bulkstat schemes to the manager.</para>
				</section>
			</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
