<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2020">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Eneo Tecnología S.L. |">
]>
<chapter>
		<title>Events</title>
	<para>In this section the user can display, analyze and manage events collected by sensors.</para>
	<para>redBorder offers maximum network visibility thanks to the many options of representation and visualization of data that our App provides. Be sure to check the sections <emphasis>Available options in the redBorder submenu</emphasis> and <emphasis>Filter events</emphasis> to discover the versatility to show only the information you want to analyze at a certain time and certain conditions. </para>
	
	<section>
		<title>Modules</title>
		<para>Redborder has a module for each main functionality. Each one uses different technologies and has an independent interface. All modules need a sensor that provides the module the data.
		</para>
		<section>
			<title>Traffic</title>
			<para>Traffic module uses netflow data to extract information about all the traffic from the sensor. The module provides information as IPs, protocols, locations and much more.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img050.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Traffic Module: Show the traffic information of the 3 sensors.</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Traffic Module: Show the traffic information of the 3 sensors.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Intrusion</title>
			<para>Intrusion modules uses data from IPS sensor to show intrusion events based on Snort signatures. It can show events such as DDoS or MITM attacks.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img051.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Intrusion Module: Shows the number of signatures that have been triggered.</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Intrusion Module: Shows the number of signatures that have been triggered.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Monitor</title>
			<para>Monitor modules uses data from SNMP, Redfish and Ipmi protocols to show the status of the infrastructure.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img052.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Monitor Module: Displays the CPU usage of the manager</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Monitor Module: Displays the CPU usage of the manager</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>	
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Social</title>
			<para>Social modules uses data from Twitter sensor to show information from that social network. It can be used to show the behaviour of the social info about a topic.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img053.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Twitter Module Dashboard</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Twitter Module Dashboard</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Vault</title>
			<para>Vault module uses syslog data to provide information about events from different origins, like the category, target, event action and more.</para>
			<para>It is also possible to expand the capabilities of the Vault module through the extensions that add compatibility with other manufacturers.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img054.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Vault Module: Displays the received syslog information.</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Vault Module: Displays the received syslog information.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Mobility</title>
			<para>Mobility module provides location information from sensors from the network APs. It can be used to show how the people is moving in a bulding.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img055.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Mobility Module</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Mobility Module</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Reports</title>
			<para>Reports module allows the user to have periodical reports with information about Redborder platform.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img056.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Example of Reports</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Example of Reports</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Modules: menu and options</title>
		<para>In the area of analysis of the menu bar (left side), we find different sections corresponding to the Apps that we have integrated into the redBorder platform.</para>
		<para>Next we will see the different options for data visualization, chart types, granularity (maximum degree of temporal detail that consults events) and attributes that can be combined to obtain a completely customized network traffic viewer.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img001.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>General view of module section</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General view of module section</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Available options in the submenu</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch06_img002.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Options in the submenu</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Options in the submenu</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold"><literal>Filters</literal>:</emphasis> allow users to isolate a portion of information for more detail. In this tab, you can view the number of filters that have been applied and perform actions on them: </para>
					<para>-<literal>Advanced Search</literal>.</para>
					<para>-<literal>Create an alarm</literal>.</para>
					<para>-<literal>Create a widget on</literal>.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img003.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Filters</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Views:</emphasis> offers different options for displaying information.</para>
					<para>-Raw: raw data events.</para>
					<para>-Tops: the total sum of data from different events to display as one. </para>
					<para>-Compare: comparison of events within a period of time.</para>
					<para>-Unique: shows events that happened only once.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img004.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Views</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Aggregation:</emphasis> there are different values or units of measure in which the data can be displayed. For example, flows per second (flows/s) or bytes per second (bps). Note that each module has its own aggregation choices.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img005.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Aggregation</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Granularity:</emphasis> indicates the degree of temporal detail that can display data. The minimum value is one minute granularity. </para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img006.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Granularity</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Graph:</emphasis> shows the different types of graphics from which we can choose to display the data. The types of charts available vary depending on the selected view. These are as follows:</para>					
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img057.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Graph type: Area</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img058.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Graph type: Line</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img059.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Graph type: Bars</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img060.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Graph type: SBars</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img061.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Graph type: Stacked</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Options:</emphasis> In this section the user can perform various actions to manage the data shown. The options vary depending on the selected view.</para>
					<para>-<literal>Show total filtered/Hide Total Filtered</literal>: Shows or hides the graph considering selected filters.</para>
					<para>-<literal>Time Machine</literal>: It allows changing the date/time of the machine to be able to view all the information and events that have elapsed in that period of time.</para>
					<para>-<literal>Sort aggregations</literal>: It allows changing the order of the aggregations shown in the module.</para>
					<para>-<literal>Export to CSV</literal>: Provides the option to export to CSV a report of any field by selecting the event limit.</para>
					<para>-<literal>Save tab as default</literal>: By selecting this option, the default tab layout can be modified.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img008.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Options</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Attributes:</emphasis> Events received by the Manager consist of a “column: value” pair. The values given in each column can be understood as data specific to the event which are the ones that really provide information. These are called “attributes”.</para>
					<para>The attributes can be displayed in several ways: as tabs or columns. <literal>Add tabs/Columns</literal> depending on the view that we are consulting.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img009.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Attributes</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<para>All attributes have specific meaning and functionality. For example, in the Traffic module we can observe very relevant attributes such as Public IP, which shows the real IP address of the devices found on the network, Public IP MAP, which indicates their position on the map, or Country Code, which indicates the country to which it belongs.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img09b.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Attributes: General vision</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Body of the screen: filtering by time range, attribute tabs and views</title>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Filter by time range:</emphasis> direct access to filtered events based on a period of time. Last 1h, 2h, 3h, 12h, 24h, last week, last month, custom filter...</para>
			<para>There is the possibility to select a different date range to those offered by default. Depending on user requirements, you can make a selection of personalized time through option <literal>Custom</literal>. Later it specifies the procedure to follow to perform a customized temporary filter.</para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Attribute tabs:</emphasis> classified network traffic information by attributes. Navigating through each of the tabs we can know in detail the values associated with the attributes that have been selected.</para>
			<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>The user can change the order in which the tabs are displayed at any time. To do this drag and drop the tab on the position where you want to put it.</para>
				<para>This section is not displayed on the Raw view.</para>
			</note>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">View:</emphasis> in this area the data is displayed according to the selected view and type of graphic. When positioning the cursor on any of the points that make up the graph, a dialog box displays in detail the information shown for that instant in time, aggregation and attribute.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img011.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>View</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>View</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Summary, search engine and data table</title>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Summary:</emphasis> under the View area is a summary relating to all loaded data displayed, both at the view and in the data table. In the following order, this summary indicates the total aggregation value of all loaded data, the total aggregation value of all loaded and selected data, the number of rows of loaded data and the value percentage added from the loaded data out of the data total. </para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Search Engine: </emphasis> allows you to search by attribute. Searches automatically become filters as we'll see a bit further.</para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Data table:</emphasis> shows the values classified by the type of selected attribute. For example, each row may be showing each of the IPs of origin (Column/Attribute: SRC Address) with the percentage detail of bytes (aggregation) that is consuming that element within the network.</para>
			<para>For the isolated analysis of one or more elements of this bar (select as filter), you need to click on the item you want to filter. For multiple selection simply hold down <keycap>Shift</keycap>.</para>
			<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>When positioning the mouse over any of the elements of the data table a menu is displayed showing the different actions that can be performed on that item. Depending on the attribute type, sort options are displayed in the context menu.</para>
			</note>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img012.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Summary, search engine and data table</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Summary, search engine and data table</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>	
	<section>
		<title>Filter events</title>
		<para>In the submenu of the section there are several options that allow us to view events according to our analysis needs.</para>
		<para>One of these options is <literal>Filters</literal> which allows the filtering of events according to the user-defined criteria. These filters can be saved to be used later as a screen for the display of events.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Filtering options:</emphasis></para>
		<itemizedlist mark="circle">
			<listitem>
				<para>Filter zoom: graphically isolated events according to a time range.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Filter Selected</literal>: allows us to convert one or more filter elements in the table.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Advanced Search</literal>: allows you to set conditions for an advanced search acting as a filter. Very useful for isolating and analyzing concrete data.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Filter actions:</emphasis></para>
		<itemizedlist mark="circle">
			<listitem>
				<para>Saved filters: shows a list of saved filters.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Create an alarm</literal>: allows us to set an alarm based on the filters applied. This action will be seen in detail in the Tools chapter (<literal>Tools</literal>).</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img013.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Tools>Alarms</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Create a widget on</literal>: creates a widget based on the search criteria that can be included in dashboards or reports. However, not all widgets can be applied to reports.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img014.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Events filtering options</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Events filtering options and available options</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Is it possible to only filter the events in a given period of time?</title>
			<para>Is possible to isolate the corresponding events to a period of time to analyze in more detail the data associated with the selected attribute.</para>
			<para>There are five ways to make a temporary filter: </para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para>Filter by time range</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Filter Zoom</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Custom filter</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Advanced search</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Filter by attribute</para>
				</listitem>	
			</itemizedlist>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Filter by time range</emphasis></para>
			<para>A simple and quick way to view only the events corresponding to a specific period of time is to select some of the options that provide tabs timeline filtering:</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="250" fileref="images/ch06_img015.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Filtering events: timeline</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Filtering events: timeline</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis role="bold"></emphasis></para>
			<para>The user can select a period of time manually. To do this, click the mouse on a specific point on the graph, drag and drop to the desired time instant. Ater that, you can see this period of time expanded in the graph.</para>	 
			<para>In the indicated submenu you will see <literal>Filter Zoom.</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img015b.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Filter Zoom</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Filtering of events: Filter Zoom</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Filter by range of time or Custom filter</emphasis></para>
			<para>The tab <literal>Custom</literal> of line filtering time range allows a custom filter. By dragging the mouse from one point to another in the month you want to consult, we will see the specific dates to be taken into account in the filtrate.Thus, we have the view for that time range and the table below show only the data contained in this strip. To do this click on the submenu <literal>Filters</literal> <literal>Start Time</literal> <literal>End Time</literal> indicated for this filter.</para>
			<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>When you perform a custom filter or <literal>Custom</literal> we can isolate in the graphic data for a period of time.</para>
			</note>
			<para>It's also possible to select the time period directly from the temporary bar that appears in the top margin.</para>
			<para>Click on <literal>Submit</literal> to apply filter.</para> 
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img017.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Filtering events: custom filter</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Filtering events by range of time: custom filter</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Advanced search</emphasis></para>
			<para>To do this click on the tab <literal>Filters</literal> that displays a submenu in which we find the option <literal>Advanced Search.</literal> </para>
			<para>This is the option that allows more detail, since it is the user who determines the conditions of the search, and therefore filtering. You can choose from all available attributes for this App. </para>
			<para>You can add as many filtering conditions as it deems necessary, just make sure to indicate the attribute, the start date and the end date you wish to consult.</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="circle">
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis>Add search rule:</emphasis> click <keycap>(+)</keycap></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis>Delete search rule:</emphasis> click <keycap>(-)</keycap></para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>To start this search, simply select the option <literal>Submit Search.</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img020.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Filtering events: advanced search</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>You can save this search settings as a filter, thus, it will be available to consult at any other time in both the option <literal>View Saved Filters</literal> as in <literal>Saved filters</literal> which you will find in the context menu of the filters.</para>
			<para>To load a saved test you can use View Saved Filters button, selecting the filter and clicking in Add Filter button.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img020_c.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Filtering events: saving filter</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Filter by attribute</emphasis></para>
			<para>There are two ways to convert a value of an attribute in a filter:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Search Engine:</emphasis> enter the attribute value you want to find and press <keycap>Enter.</keycap></para>
					<para>The chosen filter will automatically be included. You can include as many filters as searches as are conducted.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Column selection in the table:</emphasis> you can select one or more rows of the table to isolate the data relating to such elements. For multiple selection, just press the left mouse button on the ranks of the different elements you wish to filter; if you want to deselect, click again on the elements. The user can also help by pressing <keycap>Shift</keycap>. </para>
					<para>Once the rows are selected, there will be the option to include or exclude the graphical elements, as well as the data table. To go back to include them press the button <keycap>Filter Selected</keycap> located on top of the data table. To exclude them, it's necessary to press the button <keycap>Exclude Selected</keycap> located next to the previous button.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img020_a.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Include/exclude filter</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>In the case of an individual selection, its possible to perform the filter or exclusion more quickly:</para>
			<para><emphasis>a) By clicking on a name of a sensor data will be included in the view.</emphasis> In this moment, the label will display a color that corresponds to the line/area/stream/bar shown in the view. To exclude, click on it again.</para>
			<para><emphasis>b) Opening the drop-down next to each item in the table and contains the following options:</emphasis></para>
			<itemizedlist mark="circle">
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Filter:</literal> adds the appropriate filter to include the element of the data presented.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Exclude:</literal> adds the appropriate filter to exclude the element of the data presented.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Copy to clipboard:</literal> the value of the selected item is copied to the clipboard so it is available for future use.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>	
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img019.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Filtering events: Filter by attribute</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Reputation and monitoring IPs</title>
		<para>Attributes source and traffic destination (SRC Address/DST Address) allows to perform the following actions in order to facilitate a more comprehensive analysis of the origin and destination of the traffic that passes through our network:</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Create object:</emphasis> this allows to put a name and/or description allowing the location of an item more quickly and easily. For example, if we know the machine associated with a particular IP address, this option allows you to rename it for easier identification. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img021.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Renaming an IP: Create net object</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Renaming an IP: Create net object</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>We find also the option to consult outside sources to help us identify the location and reputation of the consulted IP's.</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="circle">
			<listitem>
				<para>uTrace</para> 
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Trusted Source</para> 
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Whois.sc</para> 
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch06_img022a.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>uTrace</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>uTrace</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch06_img022b.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Trusted Source</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Trusted Source</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img022c.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Whois.sc</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Whois.sc</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Basic Source Lookup:</emphasis> it is possible to obtain a complete summary of the information associated with the consulted IPs. By selecting this option a popup window will appear with two tabs: </para>
		<para><emphasis>Whois:</emphasis> shows the result of the Manager query to whois where they obtain, among other information, who owns that IP, reputation, etc.</para> 
		<para><emphasis>DNS:</emphasis> the Manager performs a reverse resolution that lets us know the DNS associated with the IP consulted.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch06_img022d.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Basic Source Lookup: information query IP/DNS</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Basic Source Lookup: information query IP/DNS</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Views: multiple options for data display</title>
		<para>Views provide multiple perspectives to display the associated data to network traffic.</para>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>Remember in the section <literal>Dashboard</literal> you can create custom widgets for each type of App indicating a type of view to display events. </para>
		</note>
		<para>The views that are available for Traffic/Vault App are: </para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Tops:</emphasis> aggregation of events based on a unit to show the most prominent. The total sum of data from different events to display as one. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Raw:</emphasis> view all raw data events, classified by attributes and time slots.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Compare:</emphasis> comparing time intervals to analyze differences in network status.</para> 
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Unique:</emphasis> shows the different elements that have interacted with the network according to attribute.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img004.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Views</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Views</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>The options shown in the tab <literal>Options</literal> and the attributes <literal>Add tab/Columns</literal> will vary according to the type of view selected.</para>
		</note>
		<important>
			<title>Important</title>
			<para>Remember to combine the views with different types of graphs. This will give you multiple possibilities for data analysis.</para>
		</important>
		<section>
			<title>Tops</title>
			<para>The Top view allows us to see what were the most prominent events as the time interval is selected. What we envision in the graph is the sum of all these events displayed as a single event. If we lay the mouse over each of these “peaks” or Tops, see the breakdown of the event by date, time and type of dimension or attribute you are checking.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img023.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Tops</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Views: Tops</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Raw</title>
			<para>This view provides raw data events, thus, we will see the total of events by segmented attributes by time slots.</para>
			<para>In the data table we will therefore collect all event data classified by columns. Data will be shown on the screen, however, if you'd like to see more, simply scroll and wait for more data to load: <emphasis>Load more.</emphasis></para>
			<para>Raw view can provide graphics in periods of 3, 5, 15 or 30 minutes.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img024.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Raw</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Views: Raw</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>As shown in the picture, the kind of graph ideal for the Raw view is data streams or <literal>Streams.</literal></para>
				<para>In the Raw view attributes are displayed in columns.</para>
			</note>
			<section>
				<title>Managing Flow events in Raw view</title>
				<para>The Raw view allows us to display all collected events by the raw Flow/Vault sensors, by attributes and segmented by time slots. Combined with a Stream graph, also displays the data flow that is occurring within the network. </para>
				<para>Each column in the data table shows the values that correspond with the selected attributes. In this table we can perform different actions:</para>
				<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
					<listitem>
						<para>Time interval or <literal> Timestamp: </literal> can see the time interval that is referenced to show the number of events that have occurred in that time.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Check event information: click on the icon “Edit” for greater granularity.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img025.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Icon “Edit"</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
						<para>When you have reached the limit of granularity at which you can display events, this icon will transform the information:</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img026.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Timestamp details: event information</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
						<para>Clicking on it we will access a screen that provides the complete information associated with each of the events set forth in that time interval.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img028.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Event information</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>

					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><literal>Create object</literal>: some of the attributes shown in the event information allow the possibility of converting into an Object. This means that these values can add a name and a description allowing the localization of an item more quickly and easily.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img027.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Create object</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<note>
					<title>Note</title>
					<para>Remember that the maximum granularity available is 1m.</para>
				</note>	
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Compare</title>
			<para>This view gives us the evolution of the use of the network by comparing two time slots. This comparison can be performed for hours or days at intervals of 5 minutes, ensuring a maximum degree of detail. Thus, the user can quickly identify the peak of network usage.</para>
			<para>In the data table which show those that correspond to the time interval selected.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img030.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Views: Compare</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Views: Compare</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Unique</title>
			<para>Through the view <literal>Unique,</literal> the user can obtain information about the different elements that have interacted, at least once with the network in a given time period. Laying the mouse on any point of the graph, the user will get the total result of unique items for the selected time period.</para>
			<para><literal>Group by</literal> (only available in the Unique view): allows us to group the data shown in the graph on the basis of a given attribute. This option provides the filtering and sorting of items according to the analysis criteria we need.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img031.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Views: Unique</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Views: Unique</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Type of aggregation</title>
		<para>The aggregation type allows the user to select the unit of measure in which you want the information to be displayed. </para>
		<para>These are the different metric units and you will find in this tab:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para>bps</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>bytes</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>packets</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>packets/s</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>flows</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>flows/s</para>
			</listitem>			
			<listitem>
				<para>client</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>quality</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>wireless stations</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>clients/station</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>bps/client</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>flows/client</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>fps/client</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>bytes/station</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>bps/station</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<note>
			<title>Nota</title>
			<para>Optimize your metric combining different types of aggregation granularity options (time periods) which are available.</para>
		</note>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img005.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Selecting the type of aggregation</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Selecting the type of aggregation</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Granularity</title>
		<para>We call granularity to the degree with which we can view events in redBorder. The options of granularity vary by time range being displayed (1h., 2h., Last week, last month, etc.). With this view the user can analyze network traffic in real time.</para>
		<para>As shown in the image according to the selected time period, the user can know the traffic detail, for example, sensor lapse of two minutes.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img032.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Metric to which a granularity of 2 minutes is applied </phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Metric that has applied a granularity of 2 minutes</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>The view <literal>Raw</literal> is the most indicated to apply granularity in order to observe the data in detail.</para>
		</note>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img033.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Combining raw view for a selected time period (granularity)</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Combining raw view for a selected time period (granularity)</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Graph type</title>
		<para>As we will see in <emphasis role="bold">Chapter 5, Dashboards</emphasis> you can select the type of graph you want to display the data provided in the different views. The options are very similar to those that are available in the process of creating custom widgets.</para>
		<para>The charts that are available at all times, will depend on the selected view. This option does not appear, for example, by applying the Map view of the data, since the data is represented in this view, on a map. These are the graphical possibilities of redBorder platform for views:</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Stacked:</emphasis> comparatively show in the same graph the data for each of the selected attributes. (In the image comparing traffic sensors).</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img034.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Stacked graph to view sensor Tops</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Stacked graph for Tops view by sensor</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Area:</emphasis> graph that provides an overlap of the data to a group of elements that belong to the selected attribute, making the total traffic the sum of the traffic by attribute (in the image, by sensor).</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img035.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Area for graphical view of Tops by SRC Address: multiple elements</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Area for graphical view of Tops by SRC Address: multiple elements</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>If they want to display on a single graphical element, just click on any point on the graph thus isolating the selected item.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img036.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Area for graphical view of Tops by Sensor: single element </phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Area for graphical view of Tops by Sensor: single element</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Line:</emphasis> graph that provides an overlap of the data to a group of elements that belong to the selected attribute; in this case the area is not displayed but the graph is represented by line.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img037.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Line graph to Tops by Sensor</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Line graph to Tops by Sensor</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Bars:</emphasis> provides an overlap of data to a group of elements that belong to the selected attribute, being the total, the value sum of each of those elements. In this case, the data is represented through bars</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img038.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Bar graphs for Tops view</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Bar graphs for Tops view</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">SBars:</emphasis> or Stacked Bars, provides in the same graph the data obtained for each of the elements included in the selected attribute, so you can view the results of independent IP, sensor, etc., represented in bars.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img039.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>SBar graphs for Tops view by SRC Address</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>SBar graphs for Tops view by SRC Address</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Streams:</emphasis> graph only available by the Raw view. Shows traffic flow by sensor.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img040.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Stream graphs (only in Raw view)</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Stream graphs (only in Raw view) </para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
	</section>	
	<section>
		<title>Options</title>
		<para>Each view has a number of options that allow the user to, among other things, display the total traffic, export the data to a CSV or take the machine to a state of the past in order to analyze and compare current and past behavior.</para>
		<para>Next all available options in this tab are listed. The user should be aware that these options vary according to the previously selected view.</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Show Total</literal>: Selecting this option is shown in the graph the value of all the differentiated traffic received or issued by each of the attributes that can be queried. When this option is active, the list of options “Hide all” appears. Available in the Top and Unique view. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Export to CSV</literal>: the user will download a file in CSV format that includes the data which corresponds to the attribute selected, it may set a limit of rows to be included in the file. Available only for Tops and Unique views.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Time machine</literal>: returns the machine to a previous state. By selecting this option the user can view the data as if he were seeing them in the last day and time you specified. Available for all views except for Raw.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Save tabs/columns as default</literal>: to apply this option, columns or tabs data have been included for analysis are displayed by default in the new consultations performed. Available for Raw, Unique and Tops views.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Sort aggregations</literal>: through this option, the user can choose the order in which the columns or tabs are displayed. Available for Raw view.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
					<para><literal>Start reloading</literal>: activates the countdown to the data reload. At any time, the user can stop this by selecting Stop reloading (Start option replaces reloading once this is enabled). At the left end of the section bar appears a countdown indicating the time out to reload. Available for Raw view.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img040a.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Options: Show total</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Options: Show total</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img041.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Options: Export to CSV</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Options: Export to CSV</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img042.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Options: Time machine</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Options: Time machine</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img043.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Options: Sort Aggregations</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Options: Sort Aggregations</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>		
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Attributes: tabs and columns</title>
		<para>The attributes help us carry out a comprehensive and personalized analysis for each of the elements involved in the flow of network traffic of our organization. These are organized into tabs or columns to the view that we are consulting. The options shown are common to all views except for the case of Compare (offers only comparability for weeks or months) and Maps, in which case this section is not shown. </para>
		<para>We also stop at two useful options for locating IPs that generate more traffic: Scatter Plot and SRC/DST MAP.</para>
		<para>Next we list the attributes that the user has available and the different aspects that we can consult of each one:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="circle">
			<listitem>
				<para>Application</para>
				<para>-Application</para>
				<para>-HTTP Host</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>-Darklist</para>
				<para>-Darklist Category</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Datalink</para>
				<para>-Client vendor</para>
				<para>-SRC Vlan</para>
				<para>-DST Vlan</para>
				<para>-TOS</para>
				<para>-Wireless ID</para>
				<para>-Client band</para>
				<para>-Client ID</para>
				<para>-Client Status</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Flow</para>
				<para>-Biflow direction</para>
				<para>-Direction</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Interface</para>
				<para>-INPUT SNMP</para>
				<para>-OUTPUT SNMP</para>
				<para>-INPUT VRF</para>
				<para>-OUTPUT VRF</para>
				<para>-Wireless Starion</para>
				<para>-Client RSSI</para>
				<para>-Client RSSI Value</para>
				<para>-Client SNR</para>
				<para>-Client SNR Value</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Location</para>
				<para>-SRC Country</para>
				<para>-SRC AS </para>
				<para>-SRC MAP </para>
				<para>-DST Country</para>
				<para>-DST AS</para>
				<para>-DST MAP</para>
				<para>-Coordinates</para>
				<para>-Coordinates Map</para>
				<para>-Service Provider</para>
				<para>-Namespace</para>
				<para>-Deployment</para>
				<para>-Market</para>
				<para>-Organization</para>
				<para>-Campus</para>
				<para>-Building</para>
				<para>-Floor</para>
				<para>-Zone</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Network</para>
				<para>-Conversation</para>
				<para>-Protocol</para>
				<para>-Protocol Version</para>
				<para>-Sensor Type</para>
				<para>-Scatterplot</para>
				<para>-SRC NET Address</para>
				<para>-DST NET Address</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Transport</para>
				<para>-SRC Port</para>
				<para>-DST Port</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Scatter Plot</emphasis></para>
		<para>In the Network attribute menu we find Scatter Plot, an option that gives us an idea of the distribution of network traffic. In a graph representing coordinate points through IPs that interact with the network traffic in real time. In the horizontal axis the show the IP destination and the coordinates, of the IP origen. The more traffic generated, the thicker the point. </para> 
		<para>Putting the mouse over each of the dots on the graph, we obtain the IP address associated with it. </para>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>Remember that any time you can isolate one or more IPs by applying filters: enter IP source and IP destination in the search box, or select one or more rows of the table. </para>
		</note>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img044.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Distribution of network traffic: Network>Scatter Plot</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Distribution of network traffic: Network>Scatter Plot</para>
			</caption>
			</mediaobject>	
			<para><emphasis role="bold">SRC/DST MAP</emphasis></para>
			<para>In the Location attribute menu we find the options SRC MAP and DST MAP. In both cases we offer the possibility to display the map which is the localization of the origin IP (SRC MAP) and destination (DST MAP) that generates the most traffic.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img045.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Location of network traffic: Location>SRC/DST MAP</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Distribution of network traffic: Location>SRC/DST MAP</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>	
			<para>When there is more than one IP connected in the same geographical point, these are clustered and displayed as a point with the biggest size that includes a number. This number indicates the total number of IPs connected at that location. For the detail of the IPs, simply apply to the map or zoom, double click on the point you want to get more information. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img046.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Location of network traffic: connection details</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Location of network traffic: connection details</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Reports</title>
		<para>Reports module is closely relationated with events. It allows the user to get customizated reports showing the information about his system.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img047.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Reports</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Reports</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>To create a new report we will click on New Report button and will fill all the fields. Here we can select parameters like schedule type, sharing users or sharing domains. Once the report is created it will be shown in the report list seen before.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img048.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Reports</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Reports</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Is also possible to import a report from a file using Import Report button.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch06_img049.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Reports</phrase>
			</textobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Reports</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>In the report list we have the possibility to edit an existing report or also generate it in PDF or send it by email, all this options are in the edit button in the right of the list.</para>
		<para>The blocks of the report can be also modified choosing the block edit option in the report list, where the user will be able to add, move and delete any kind of block for the report.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
