<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2020">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Eneo Tecnología S.L. |">
]>
<chapter>
	<title>Tools and Administration</title>
	<para>On the right side of the menu bar, next to the menu <literal>Sensors</literal> we find the “tools” section or <literal>Tools</literal> where you can find the options for the configuration of the redBorder platform.</para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img001.png"/>
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para><literal>Tools:</literal> available options for configuring the redBorder platform </para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	<para>From this menu you can establish the conditions to be met so that the user is notified by an alarm, track the activities of the users of the platform, to register new users or to manage cluster configuration, sensors and servers, among other actions.</para>
	<para>These are the options found in the tool menu:</para>
	<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Alarms</literal>: establishing the conditions for activating a user notification.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Audits</literal>: allows tracking of user activity using log.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Cluster Settings</literal>: shows us the settings that have been established for the cluster in the Manager installation process.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>General Settings</literal>: the user can establish the general parameter settings of the Manager, as well as the Apps they have registered. </para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Correlation Engine Rules</literal>: provides the list of the cep rules. Here we can also check the existing rules and create new ones.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Monitor Categories</literal>: shows the current categories being used from snmp and allows the creation of new ones.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Licenses</literal>: list of the licenses under those that operate the different modules of the redBorder platform.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Lookup Sources</literal>: list of URLs of web services of network data consultation.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Objects</literal>: network objects defined in the redBorder platform.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Overlay Maps</literal>: images that can be superimposed on a map with the latitude and longitude indicated.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Platform Alerts</literal>: shows the current platform alert to every user.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Rule Versions</literal>: list of the licenses under those that operate the different modules of the redBorder platform.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Support Center</literal>: direct access to support center. It is necessary to be registered in support page.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Users</literal>: profile management and user permissions.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Worker and Job Queue</literal>: show the current active and stored workers and jobs on Redborder manager.</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<section>
		<title>Alarms</title>
		<para>An alarm is a notification that is triggered when one or more conditions are met by the user.</para>
		<para>By accessing this option the list of alarms that have been registered are displayed.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img002.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>List of active alarms</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Create new alarm</title>
			<para>By clicking on the button <literal>+New Alarm</literal> we access the form, in which the conditions will be established that the alarm must meet to activate a notification, and the degree of severity defined for that alarm.</para>
			<para>This form consists of three sections:</para>
			<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
				<listitem>
					<para>General settings</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Notifications</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Conditions</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch06_img013.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Create a new alarm</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">General settings</emphasis></para>
			<para>In this section, the user must complete the following data:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Name</literal>: alarm name.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Time window</literal>: time interval that must be overcome by excess or default values given in <literal>upper/bottom limit</literal> so that the alarm is active.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Notify every</literal>: set time sequence for notification.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Upper/ Bottom limits</literal>: indicates the number of events (maximum/minimum) that must meet the conditions of the alarm to activate the notification.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Product type</literal>: select the type of App/item for which the alarm has defined. <footnote><para>The user will see in this field options that are included in their license.</para></footnote></para>
					<para>-Traffic</para>
					<para>-Intrussion</para>
					<para>-Monitor</para>
					<para>-Social</para>
					<para>-Vault</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Severity:</literal> the user must define the severity level that's given to the alarm. Depending on the conditions you have defined for the alarm will imply a very low risk, low, medium, high, very high or critical. This gradation of severity is also indicated on a color scale. </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Notifications</emphasis></para>
			<para>In this section, the user will select the means by which the alarm is notified and will introduce the data for the method chosen. Activate the check option you want for the notification:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Notify to Syslog</literal>: check that to export the notifications to an external syslog server.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Notify to email</literal>: check that to receive an email when a alarm is raised.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Audits</title>
		<para>Option <literal>Audits</literal>This option shows a list of the recorded user activity in the redBorder platform, chronologically ordered, by default.. However, the user can sort the table in an ascending or descending way for each of the columns. You can use the search box located on the top to filter the information you want to see. The columns displayed in this table are the following: </para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>User</literal>: user that did the action</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Resource</literal>: item that has been created, modified, or deleted. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Action</literal>: action that has been carried out (creating, editing, deleting).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Message</literal>: brief description of what has been audited.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Timestamp</literal>: date and time of the activity record.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img004.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Audits: user activity record</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Cluster Settings</title>
		<para>Option <literal>Cluster Settings</literal> allows us to check the status and cluster settings, set the cluster creation process during the Manager installation process.</para>
		<para>You can modify these values by editing through the unlock button <literal>Unlock.</literal> The information can be changed with the following parameters:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para>Cluster Status</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Virtual IP Addresses</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Historical Nodes</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Historical Rules</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img005.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Cluster Settings: status and cluster settings</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>General settings</title>
		<para>Option <literal>General Settings</literal> shows us an interface whose editing will be determined for both the platform configuration, as well as the network infrastructure, as it was explained in the chapter about sensors.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img006.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General Settings: general settings for redBorder Manager</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>To view all sections, it's advised to enable the option <literal>Show advanced options</literal> located on the top right of the screen in general settings.</para>
			<para>In this screen you can edit the parameters of both the Manager and the Apps that have been registered. Therefore, the sections displayed will depend on the Apps that are integrated into the redBorder platform.</para>
		</note>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img008.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General Settings: advanced options</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		<para>To perform a basic configuration in Manager, the user can edit general parameters, characteristics of the Apps, server configuration, network, routes and geolocation of the IPs. </para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">General parameters</emphasis></para>
		<para>In this section the user can change the following elements:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="circle">
			<listitem>
				<para><literal> Company name</literal>: Name of the company using Redborder</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Company email</literal>: Company email. Will be used as the report sender and license management</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Web URL</literal>: Interface URL</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Autoreload dashboard time</literal>: Refresh period for the dashboards (seconds)</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Autoreload raw time</literal>: Refresh period for the interface (seconds)</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Rule Update Job Periodicity</literal>: Periodicity for updating the Rules</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><literal>Rule Update Job Time</literal> UTC time when the Rule Update Job will be executed</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img006.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General settings: editing general parameters</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<important>
			<title>Important</title>
			<para>All parameters defined in this interface are inherited by those elements that are found on lower levels in a dependent state (domains, sensors). To modify this information, the user must write or edit it, as described in the chapter about editing sensors and configuration <literal>Sensors.</literal></para>
		</important>	
		<para><emphasis role="bold">IPS/IDS Settings</emphasis></para>
		<para>Here we can set in Redborder the IPS/IDS physical setup and configuration.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_a.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General settings: IPS/IDS Settings</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">HTTP SSL Certificates</emphasis></para>
		<para>Allows to set a SSL certificate for secure communications.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_b.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General settings: IPS/IDS Settings</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Servers</emphasis></para>
		<para>Configuration of servers Syslog, MTA, NTP and enable proxy settings.</para>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>An example of how to configure servers is in Chapter 11, “Editing sensor and/or domain."</para>
		</note>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_c.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General settings: server configuration</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Default Rules</emphasis></para>
		<para>Configuration of Default Rules for loading or dropping data.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_d.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General settings: Default Rules</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Monitoring and Logs</emphasis></para>
		<para>This section helps you to momitorize redBorder infrastructure. In the field <literal>Syslog Servers</literal> you have to indicate in which remote server, logs are going to be sent. </para>
		<para>You must select which protocol and which Syslog mode you want to use for the sendings.</para>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>TCP protocol is recommended in order to guarantee a safe sending. Choose this option whenever possible.</para>
		</note>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_e.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General Settings: Monitoring and logs</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>The section New Relic allows you to report to New Relic cloud. In this case, the user have to indicate the number of their New Relic License and if they have a Cluster group, write its name.</para>
		<para>The activation of <literal>Enable Plugins</literal> check is optional because this is a payment service. Activate <literal> Enable APM</literal> in case of web monitoring.</para>

		<para><emphasis role="bold">Amazon CloudWatch</emphasis></para>
		<para>If user wants to send their logs to this Amazon Service, required fields must be filled.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_f.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General Settings: Amazon CloudWatch</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Google Maps API</emphasis></para>
		<para>Is possible to link Redborder with Google Maps API to get better location information.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_g.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General Settings: Google Maps API</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Backup segments (Remote S3)</emphasis></para>
		<para>It enables a backup of user's data in a remote server or database. For this, it is necessary to indicate Hostname, Bucket, and Access and Secret key. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch13_img009_h.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General Settings: Backup segments (Remote S3)</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">White networks</emphasis></para>
		<para>In this section the networks are indicated whose traffic will pass without package inspection, because the networks are considered “reliable.”</para>
		<para>Add a new network: click the button <literal>+Add</literal> and indicate the network IP.</para>
		<para>Delete a network from the list: through the icon “Delete".</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_i.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General settings: Add a new White Network</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Black Networks</emphasis></para>
		<para>List of networks whose traffic should be blocked because of the bad reputation.</para>
		<para>Add a new network: just click on the button <literal>+Add</literal> and indicate the network IP.</para>
		<para>Delete a network from the list: through the icon “Delete".</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_j.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General settings: Add a new Black Network</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold"><literal>Network Routes</literal></emphasis></para>
		<para>In this section the user will define the network routes for Manager. </para>
		<para>Add a new network: click on the button <literal>+Add</literal> and indicate the network IP route.</para>
		<para>Delete a network from the list: through the icon “Delete”.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_k.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General settings: list of Network Routes</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold"><literal>Fixed Hosts</literal></emphasis></para>
		<para>In this section the user will define the network routes for Manager. </para>
		<para>Add a new network: click on the button <literal>+Add</literal> and indicate the network IP route.</para>
		<para>Delete a network from the list: through the icon “Delete”.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_l.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General settings: list of Network Routes</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Geo IP</emphasis></para>
		<para>To enable Geo Protection function it is necessary to have an updated geolocalization database in order to avoid errors in IPs geolocalization. redBorder has been configured to support only Maxmind database format.</para>
		<para>These are the types of databases that are admitted for IPv4 and IPv6 versions (binary format of old GeoIp):</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para>Country: it determines the country of an Internet visitor based on their IP Address.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>City: it indicates the country, subdivisions, city, postcode, latitude and longitude associated with IPv4 and IPv6  worldwide addresses.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>ASN: GeoIP2 database of anonymous IP contains data about IP addresses of the networks that have been used in a various ways by anonymous. </para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Download all the files from Maxmind website and unzip them. It is only possible to upload files with .dat format as we can see in the image below. For this, click on <literal>+Select File</literal></para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img009_m.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General settings: GeoIP Protection</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Correlation Engine Rules</title>
		<para>Here the use can see all the rules for the correlation engine. It is possible to edit the existing rules and also create new ones.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img014.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Correlator Engine Rules</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Monitor Categories</title>
		<para>Here we can add a new category to monitorize the hardware. The categories use technologies such as SNMP, Redfish or IPMI to provide information about the system and its functioning.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img013.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Monitor Categories</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>To add a new monitor category we must use the top right button. Then we will fill the fields selecting the correct technology allowing Redborder to receive the data.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img013_b.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Infrastructure Monitor</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>SNMP Operation</title>			
			<para>To explain the feature snmp operation we will use an example, monitor memory usage. When we create a new monitor category using the New Monitor Category button from the Monitor Categories page, we will see the following popup.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img013_c.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Initial creation of a monitor category</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		<para>This is the formula to calculate the memory usage of a device:</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img013_d.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>	
		<para>The result is a combination of different snmp values. Now, if we want to create a monitor as the one in this example, we must choose SNMP Operation in the technology dropdown. Now our form will change to the following:</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img013_d.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Create monitor with SNMP Operation</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Under the OID field, now there is a button called Add new variable, which adds another field so we can enter more snmp OIDs. Also, at the bottom, there is an OIDs Operation field, in which we will introduce the operation we want to do with the OIDs previously entered.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img013_e.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Example monitor</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>For every OID the output is going to be stored on a varaible which we will later used in the OIDs operation.</para>
		<para>Once at this point, we just have to create the monitor by pressing the create button.</para>
		<para>To add the new monitor to a sensor device we will create a new sensor in Sensor tab, selecting Monitor Device.</para>


		</section>

	</section>	
	<section>
		<title>Licenses</title>
		<para>Through this option the user can check which nodes have their liceses expired. In the same, it is possible to upload a new license or request for a new one.</para>
		<para>On the top edge of the screen there are indicated the number of available licenses, the Apps that can be used under these licenses and the number of expired nodes. There is a list of expired nodes which need to renew their licenses at the center of screen. There is also a list of the available actions.</para>
		<para>To upload a file with a new redBorder license, click on <literal>Select file.</literal> To request a new license click on <literal>Request a license.</literal></para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img015.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Licenses: queries and updating of expired licenses</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Lookup Sources</title>
		<para>List of the web services URLs which perform the network data queries. From this screen it is possible to add more web services, as well as edit the existing ones.</para>
		<para>Delete a service: click on "Delete" button.</para>
		<para>Edit an existing service: click on "Edit" button:</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img016.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Lookup Sources: queries web services</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Add new web service: click on the button <literal>+Add Lookup Source.</literal></para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img017.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Add a new Lookup Source</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Objets</title>
		<para>The option <literal>Objects</literal> allows the direct creation and edition of Objects. The user can navigate through different tabs that corresponding to the types of objects that can be created. If you want to locate the objects in a more efficiently way you can use the browser.</para>
		<para>Three kind of objects can be created:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="circle">
			<listitem>
				<para>Net</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>MAC</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>VLAN</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img018.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Objects: list of objects</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Create a new object: click on <literal>New (Net, MAC, VLAN) Object</literal></para>
		<para>Edit an existing object: click on "Edit" button.</para>
		<para>Delete an object: click on the "Delete" icon.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img019.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Objects: create a new net object</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>In all cases when you are creating or editing an object, the system asks you for a name, a value for it and description.</para>
		<para>In the top right margin an options submenu is shown. It allows user to import or export the data concerning these objects in .csv format.</para>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>It is possible to create an object directly from the attributes that are shown in the tables, as in Flow App as IPS. For this, click the inverted narrow that appears when we pass the mouse over an attribute like IP, MAC or VLAN. </para>
		</note>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Overlay Maps</title>
		<para>This option allows to overlay an image over a Google map in order to get more customization.</para>
		<para>Edit Map: click on the "Edit" button  positioned next to the existing maps list.</para>
		<para>Add new map: click on <literal>+New Overlay Map.</literal></para>
		<para>In both cases, it will be indicated the name of the map, latitude and longitud in where the image should be located. </para>
		<para>Por último, subir la imagen desde su equipo en formato .jpg o .png.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch13_img020.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para><literal>Overlay Map:</literal> overlay images over a world map</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Platform Alerts</title>
		<para>Here the user can see the alerts from the platform. All the alerts are shown to every user.</para>
		<para>There are three levels for the alerts: info, warning and danger. Each level has its own colour so the alerts can be differenced.</para>

		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch13_img021_a.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para><literal>Platform Alerts</literal></para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Is possible to create alerts for the platform using the New Alert button. Is necessary to select the alert level, and the message of the alert.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch13_img021_b.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para><literal>Platform Alerts: New Alert</literal></para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>If the alert message is clicked by the user, it won't be shown again until the user logs in again.</para>
		<para>Is possible to remove the alert by clicking on the cross in the message. After that the alert message won't be shown anymore.</para>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Rule Versions</title>
		<para>The user can manage the sources for the rules of the platform. It is possible to add or upload new sources and also enable the chosen ones. The rules are used for Snort probe, which is used by traffic module.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch13_img022.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para><literal>Rule Versions</literal></para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		<para>It is possible to upload rules for a particular IPS using the option Upload Source, where the user can select the file to upload.</para>
		<para>It is also possible to add sources for downloading new rules from the internet that are updated periodically. If it is necessary the user can use the Force Rule Update to be sure that all the rules are updated.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Support Center</title>
		<para>The user can use the Support Center in order to solve any question or problem regarding the platform. It is necessary to be registered in the Support Center.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch13_img023.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para><literal>Support Center</literal></para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Users</title>
		<para>The activation or modification of users' data, services management or the creation of new registers is possible from the <literal>Users settings </literal> interface.</para>
		<para>To search a specific user, introduce their data in the browser. You can also navigate through the alphabetic list that is located on top of users list.</para>
		<para>The only user that has permissions to do that is Superadministrator. The rest of the users can only visualize the sections of the platform (reading mode) but not modify its content (except in the case of its own user profile).</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img024_a.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Users: management users'permissions interface</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>In the body of the screen we find a list that contains the active users in redBorder platform, email address, Top Domain (maximun level that the user has access), number of times that they have signed in, IP and hour from which they made their last access. </para>
		<para>Clicking on the "Edit" button the user can modify the following information and visualize a summary of their state and activity within the platform: </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch13_img024_b.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Users: user's profile edition</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<important>
			<title>Important</title>
			<para>Every time that any data in a user's profile is modified, the current password should be introduced to confirm the changes.</para>
		</important>
		<para>Active a new user: to create a new user click on <literal>+New User.</literal> Complete the information required in the user's profile. Active <literal>Administrator</literal> check to obtain full permissions.</para>	
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch13_img024_c.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Users: New user</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
        <title>Worker and job queue</title>
        <para>In this option the user can check the status of work <literal>(Worker)</literal> and services <literal>(Job)</literal> that are running in the background. You can also check which of these tasks have been completed.</para>
        <note>
            <title>Note</title>
            <para>We call <literal>Worker</literal> programs that are steadily running in the background.</para>
            <para>A <literal>Job</literal> is a program that runs periodically or only once, but it does not stay running in the background, but runs and closes.</para>
        </note>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch13_img025_a.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>¡Worker and Job Queue: status list of worker and job queue.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para><literal>Stored Jobs</literal> shows the list of finished services. You can know the status of each one through the “Information” icon, or delete from the list using the “Delete” icon.</para>
        <para>This screen automatically reloads every 5 seconds.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch13_img025_b.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Worker and Job Queue: information of the state of a work</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>User area</title>
        <para>At the top right of the menu bar you find the user area, from which you can view notifications, check the profile, access context-sensitive help and exit the system.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img026.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>User area</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para><literal>Notifications</literal></para>
        <para>To view a summary list of notifications simply click on <literal>User's area.</literal> To access a complete list of them, select the option <literal>View All</literal> or click on any of the notifications that appear in the summary; in this way you can access a new screen from which you can view the details of notifications, and remove all of them through the option <literal>Delete All</literal>.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img027.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				   <para>User area: Notifications</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><literal>My profile</literal></para>
		<para>This option allows direct access to the user profile and perform the same actions with the option <literal>Tools>Users</literal>.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch13_img024_b.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				 <para>Users: editing user profile</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><literal>Show help</literal></para>
		<para>This option enables a context-sensitive help that facilitates navigation and usability of the platform.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img029.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				 <para>User area: Help</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para><literal>Logout</literal></para>
		<para>For safe disconnection of the platform, select the option <literal>Logout.</literal> The system will return to the login screen.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="450" align="center" fileref="images/ch13_img030.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				  <para>User area: login screen after Logout</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>		
</chapter>
