<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2022">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Eneo Tecnología S.L. |">
]>
<chapter>
		<title>Installing redBorder Manager Enterprise</title>
		<para>Welcome to the installation of redBorder Enterprise solution. Thanks to this guide, anyone can set up the platform without having knowledge of specific programming from Linux</para>
		<para>Installing the redborder Enterprise Manager edition is the first step to start monitoring and securing your network data with the redborder solution. You should check the contents of this chapter before beginning the installation of the platform (also referred as the redborder Manager).</para>
	<section> 
		<title>Obtaining the ISO</title>
		<para>Redborder Enterprise Edition is distributed as an ISO file that can be obtained in different ways. If you don’t have the ISO file, please contact our sales team (sales@redborder.com) or our support team (support@redborder.com) to provide you the last available ISO file or a way to download it.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Burning / Handling the ISO Image</title>
		<para>In case of installation on physical machine, it is possible to burn the ISO image on a DVD or USB storage device to proceed with its installation</para>
		<para>In case of installation in virtual machine, it will be enough to mount the ISO image in a virtual DVD device.</para>
	</section>
	<section> 
		<title>Installation Requirements</title>
		<para>The following requirements are related to a single node installation with light to moderate use. Please consider that if you run the platform in a virtual environment you should usually get the performance somehow decreased comparing to a similar physical machine deployment.</para>
		<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img001.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>Redborder single node installation requirements</phrase>
					</textobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Redborder single node installation requirements</para>
					</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Installation Process</title>
		<para>As soon as your system boots with the redborder ISO image you will see the redborder Enterprise installation Welcome Screen with useful options related to the operation of your computer..</para>
		<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch02_img002.png"/> <!-- TODO Change picture and Install Gateway Sensor option-->
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>Redborder Enterprise installation wellcome screen</phrase>
					</textobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Redborder Enterprise installation wellcome screen</para>
					</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Install Manager</literal>: Performs Manager software installation on the computer.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Rescue installed System</literal>: start rescue mode in those cases which there are problems booting your machine (advanced mode).</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Boot from Local Drive</literal>: Booting from local disk (default).</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><literal>Memory Test</literal>: Memory testing available for installation system.</para>
		</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Select <emphasis role="bold">Install Manager</emphasis> option to start the installation process.</para>
		<para>System will show a screen to select the drive to install the platform, the root user password and the Licensing model:</para>
		<para>Thanks to the installation wizard you can leave the manager configured and ready quickly and easily without having the need for special programming skills in Linux.</para>  
		<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch02_img004.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>Installing with simple wizard</phrase>
					</textobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Installing with simple wizard</para>
					</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>You can also follow a complete guide from our support page by accessing this link: <emphasis role="bold">https://support.redborder.com/hc/en-us/articles/360000962497-RedBorder-Enterprise-Installation-Guide</emphasis></para>
	    </note>
	</section>
	<section>	
		<title>Possible drawbacks during installation.</title>
		<para>It is unlikely, but possible that errors may occur during the installation process. Some of them will be mentioned in this guide, and how to solve it.</para>
		<important>
		<title>Important</title>
		<para>Once the installation is complete with 100%, before reboot it's <emphasis role="bold">VERY IMPORTANT</emphasis> to remove the USB from the computer or it will recognize it as part of the HD structure, and then fail.</para>
		</important>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Error Parsing Kickstart Config</emphasis></para>
		<para>After partitioning the disk in the installation process, the partition will be named <emphasis role="bold">VolGroup</emphasis> by default. If you perform a second manager installation later (without renaming the group volume), you will get this error.</para>
		<para>To fix it, it's as simple as <emphasis role="bold">removing the volgroup</emphasis>. You can use <emphasis role="bold">Gparted</emphasis> to perform this action.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Anaconda Exception Occurred</emphasis></para>
		<para>This error indicates that the volume group name "VolGroup" is already in use. This is due to a bad burn of the ISO in the bootable USB or a bad partition in the HD before the installation.</para>
		<para>The solution is to <emphasis role="bold">recreate a new bootable usb</emphasis> making sure there are no errors. As indicated in the guide mentioned above, in order to burn the ISO image from a Linux system to a USB device, you can use <emphasis role="bold">dd command.</emphasis></para>
	</section>		
</chapter>
