<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2015">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Eneo Tecnología S.L. |">
]>

<chapter>
	<title>Sensors</title>
	<para>In <literal>Sensors</literal> this section the user can make queries, manage and make configurations of their network infrastructure through the creation and edition of domains and sensors. There are many views that offer the possibility to make different actions on their network elements.</para>
	<para><literal>Sensors</literal> is available in the top right margin of the header menu, next to <emphasis role="bold">Tools</emphasis> section and User's Area. This menu area is named as <emphasis role="bold">Configuration</emphasis> zone, because unlike the options available in the top left margin (Analysis), these allow the complete management and configuration of the Manager and sensors: rules policies, alarms, cluster configuration or user's management, among other actions.</para>
	<section>
		<title>Sensors: menu and options</title>
		<para>The organization of this sections is very similar (in terms of structure) to the other parts of the web. We can find in this case:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Section submenu:</emphasis> configuration and sensors'management options.</para>
				<para>-<literal>Options</literal></para>
				<para>-<literal>+Add sensor</literal></para>
				<para>-<literal>+Add Domain</literal></para>
				<para>-<literal>View</literal></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Main area:</emphasis> the information that is shown in this area depends on the selected <literal>View.</literal> There are four available views in order to visualize our network infrastructure:</para>
				<para>-<literal>Tree</literal>: list with the different levels that compose the network infrastructure classified by dependency and hierarchy. Alongside each element are two icons for editing and deleting actions. This is the view that is displayed by default.</para>
				<para>-<literal>Map</literal>: locate the domains and sensors over a map.</para>
				<para>-<literal>Access Points</literal>: direct access to the visualization of the deployed Access Points.</para>
				<para>-Sensors: in the <literal>View</literal> submenu, the user can find a list of available sensors depending on the Apps included in your license. Click on the sensor you want to check for view an alphabetic list of all the sensors associated with this App.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img001.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>General view of Sensors section</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>Each view has its own options menu and the different possibilities of creation and edition of the sensors or domains.</para>
			<para>Map view hasn't any available option.</para>
			<para>Policy management will be explained in another chapter.</para>
		</note>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>View</title>
		<para>When the user access to the <literal>Sensors</literal> section can find a list (Tree view) in which the domains and sensors that are a part of their network infrastructure are shown. In this point we are going to review each view and the actions available.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img002.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>View menu: options</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Tree view</title>
			<para><literal>Tree</literal> view is shown by default in the Sensors section. It is a list with the different levels that compose the network infrastructure classified by dependency and hierarchy. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img004.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Tree view</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>From this view, the user can add a new domain or sensor, delete the existing, access to other views, import and export the tree as well as direct editing of all the domains and sensors that are a part of the list.</para>
			<para>Every element that is shown in the tree has two icons: Edit and Delete. (The same icons work in tree and sensors view):</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img004b.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>"Edit" and "Delete" icons</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>The options in the <emphasis role="bold">Edit menu</emphasis> can change depending on if we are consulting the infrastructure at domain or at sensor level.</para>
			</note>
			<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Some sensors can't be deleted.</emphasis>  In these cases, the "Delete" icon will appear colored in grey.</para>
				<para>Before the domain or sensor will be deleted, the system will show you a pop-up screen with a warning message. All the users and descendants assigned to this domain or sensor will be disable and assigned to the parents of this domain or root domain. The user with Administrator role should activate user's permissions from <literal>Tools>Users</literal> section.</para>
			</note>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center"  fileref="images/ch11_img003.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Confirm the deleting of the sensor</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>In this view we can find also an icon that indicates the type of policy that regulate for each domain or (IPS) sensor. Click on this icon to access the interface for this policy and from which we can perform some different actions. We'll see that in detail in the <emphasis>Policy rules</emphasis> chapter.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img004c.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Policy icon</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Infrastructure organization levels in redBorder</title>
				<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Domain:</emphasis> containers which may include sensors, group of sensors, etc.</para>
						<para>Domain level shows us the domain name and allows us to add a description. It is possible to classify them according to their nature (organizational, spacial, etc.); each one will have an identifying icon:</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Generic</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Service Provider</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Organization: it is possible to add more sections in order to classify the sensor within the organization.</para>
						<para>-Organization details</para>
						<para>-Head Office</para>
						<para>-Billing</para>
						<para>-Accounting</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Market</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Deployment</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Namespace</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Campus</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Building</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Floor</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Sensors:</emphasis> end nodes that correspond with physical elements placed on the network (switches, routers, IPS, etc.).</para>
						<para>The information in sensor level is: sensor name, IP, policy (IPS sensors), last check and version. It is possible to add a description to the sensor.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img004a.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Detail of organization levels in a sensor infrastructures</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<note>
					<title>Note</title>
					<para>Note that to create IPS sensors you must do that through the registration of the sensors in the Manager in the Manager Installation process. From this section you can edit and overwrite the parameters that they have inherited from General Settings.</para>
					<para>The sensors of the rest of the Apps can be created from <literal>Sensors</literal> section.</para>
				</note>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Configuration inheritance</emphasis></para>
				<para>In <literal>Tools</literal> section we find <literal>General Settings</literal> option from which the user can define general parameters of the Manager and Apps. </para>
				<para>This is the maximum level of configuration (it acts as <literal>root</literal> domain) therefore, the properties defined here will be inherited by domains and sensors that fall below this level.</para>
				<para>When a domain or sensor is created or it is edited for the first time, we can observe that some parameters have the tag "Inherited", it means that they have inherited the values from General Settings. Overwrite this information in case that you want to change it.</para>
				<para>The domains and sensors that fall below the level of the element overwritten, inherit again, the properties applied to this element.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Import Tree</title>
				<para>This option allows to import your network infrastructure through the uploading of a file to redBorder platform. This will be shown in tree view.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img005.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Import Tree</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>There are two ways to import tree: </para>
				<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
					<listitem>
						<para><literal>Options>Import tree</literal></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Edit icon (domain level)</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img006.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Import/Export tree from <literal>Options</literal> menu</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img008.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Import/Export tree through Edit icon (domain level)</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Export Tree</title>
				<para>This option allows to export a tree and is within easy reach for other applications. User will download a zip file for storing then in their computer.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img007.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Export Tree</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>There are two ways to export a tree: </para>
				<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
					<listitem>
						<para><literal>Options> Export tree</literal></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Edit icon (domain level)</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Monitors</title>
				<note>
					<title>Note</title>
					<para>This option is only available in the Edit icon menu (sensor level).</para>
				</note>
				<para>Click on sensor's Edit icon and select <literal>Monitor</literal> option. Then, we can see a list with the monitoring metrics that can be applied to the sensor.</para>
				<para><literal>Technology</literal> column indicates the origin from where the data is collected.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img010.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Monitors</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Restore default:</emphasis> applies default metrics that are included in sensors creation.</para>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Add monitor:</emphasis> shows available metrics.</para>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Delete monitor:</emphasis> delete the metric applied.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch11_img011.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Add Monitor: available metrics</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Map view</title>
			<para>In this view, the user can see where the domains and sensors are located. There aren't any options available here. However, it is possible to add a new location, both for a new domain/sensor and for an existing one.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch11_img012.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para><literal>Map</literal> view</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Add location</emphasis></para>
			<para>To add a sensor to <literal>Map</literal> view it’s necessary to add first a location in the domain or sensor editing interface that has been selected. </para>
			<para>For this, you can edit them when you add a new one (<literal>+Add Sensor/Domain</literal>) or by editing an existing one using the Edit icon.</para>
			<para>In both cases you will find a paragraph called <literal>Location</literal> in which a Map is shown; you can find the desired location or point by clicking on the map. Then select <literal>+Add Location</literal> tab.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch11_img014.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Create/Edit sensor: Location</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>The coordinates fields will be filled, in case of, you previously point or search this location. Otherwise, insert Latitude and Longitude values manually.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img013.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Define coordinates to add a location for a sensor or domain</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>View Access Points</title>
			<para>Access Points (AP) are access points of the network infrastructure which are associated with a location. The Access Points depend on the Flow App and apply to both the domain level, as well as the sensors.</para>
			<para>This is another way to display your network infrastructure, through the distribution of the APs per domain, and you can also view the status of each AP. You can access the display or create access points in two different ways:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para>View>Access Points</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img016.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>View>Access Points</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Edit icon to sensor/domain level>Edit: <literal>View Access Points</literal> (located in the submenu upper right side).</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img017.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Edit domain/sensor>View Access Points</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>To find out which level you are, you can check the shipping route in the upper left margin. You can browse through the different screens by clicking on any of the items of the route.</para>
			</note>
			<para>The submenu of this interface shows a series of buttons similar to those on the main screen <literal>Sensors.</literal> The actions you can perform from this screen are as follows (these vary depending on whether it is consulting a domain or sensor level):</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Show Map</literal>/<literal>Show Floors</literal>: shows the geographical distribution of access points or its plant location in the case we are consulting a domain <literal>Floor</literal> with more than a floor level.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Edit (sensor name or domain): we return to the editing screen for the domain or sensor.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Options><literal>Options>Export Access Points/Delete All Access Points.</literal>: allows you to export all Access Points a a .csv file or delete all the Access Points defined for that localization. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>+Add sensors</literal>: add sensors to the doman we are consulting. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>+Add Domain</literal></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>View</literal>: menu that allows us to navigate through the different existing views.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img018.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Access Points interface (domain level)</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img018b.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Access Point summary</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img018c.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Access Point's information detail</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img019.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Add a new Access Point zone</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>View sensors</title>
			<para>The sensor views provide us the possibility to know at a single glance which sensors of each App is associate with the Manager. Therefore, to access this view the user must select the type of sensors they want to query. Once they have agreed to this view, the user can view a list of all sensors of this type. </para>
			<para>This view is very useful to display all of the sensors together, according to their type and the information they provide us.</para>
			<para>This list is organized alphabetically. Both the amount table columns and available options will vary depending on the type of sensor that is chosen. </para>
			<para>From this view it is possible to directly create a new sensor type you are consulting. This sensor will appear as dependent to the top level or <literal>Root</literal> and will inherit all your settings. To place it on another level, to include it within a domain or determine their dependence, you should do it from the tree view.</para>
			<para>To edit the settings, click on the Edit button.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img016.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Sensor views: details of sensors that are available to consult </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>To consult the sensors the user can perform a search, or alphabetically browse by the list of sensors. </para>	
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img020.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Flow Sensor Views: available information</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Add and/or edit a domain</title>	
		<para>redBorder lets you organize your network infrastructure around a number of domains or containers that identify the nature, value or location of the sensors that are part of it.</para>
		<para>As seen above, there are several types of domains identified by an icon in the tree view. The process of adding a domain is very simple; settings must be made later by the edit button found in the tree view or <literal>Access Points</literal>.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Add a new domain</title>
			<para>Select option <literal>+Add Domain</literal> which is located in the upper right submenu, choose the type of domain you want to add, and then fill out the required fields (these vary depending on the type of domain to be created).</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img021.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Add a domain: domain selection</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img022.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Add a domain: fill in the data to create</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>From this moment, the rest of the information associated with the domain will need to be modified by clicking the edit button to the right of each domain in the tree view, or <literal>Access Points</literal> and selecting the option <literal>Edit.</literal></para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Edit a domain</title>
			<para>From this interface you can modify the settings of an existing domain, and enter the information of a newly created domain.</para>
			<para>To access this screen the user must click the edit button to the right of the domain you want to edit from the tree view or <literal>Access Points</literal> and select the option <literal>Edit.</literal></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img023.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Example of editing a domain</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>This is the general data that we can modify for the domains. However, depending on the type of domain selected, one of these fields will appear:</para>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>General:</literal> displays general information of the sensor. Name (not editable from the Web), type of domain-select the domain type in the box) and description.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img023b.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>General information for editing a domain</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>	
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Servers</literal>: In this section the user can define the configuration of the Proxy and Syslog servers. All values shown are inherited by default. Overwrite if necessary</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img024.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Configuring Proxy and Syslog servers</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Location</literal>: Locate the sensor/domain on a world map. This location will be displayed in the view <literal>Map.</literal></para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>	
		</section>
	</section>			
	<section>
		<title>Add and/or edit a sensor</title>
		<para>redBorder allows the creation of sensors within the platform for collecting data through them. The type of sensors that can be added will depend on the apps that are active under its license. Different types of sensors are identified by an icon that is displayed in both the tree view and in the sensors and <literal>Access Points</literal>.</para>
		<para>The process of adding a sensor is very simple; configurations must be made later by the edit button found in the tree view, sensors or <literal>Access Points</literal>.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Add a sensor</title>
			<para>Among the submenu options, we find <literal>+Add Sensor.</literal> In the dropdown menu they show the different sensors available to add to the network infrastructure.</para>
			<para>Select the type of sensor in the drop-down menu, and then complete the information requested.</para>
			<para>From this point, you can configure the other information associated with the sensor from the various editing options and settings that are explained below, and are available from the tree view, sensor and <literal>Access Points</literal>.</para>
			<para>Remember that to manage the hierarchy of sensors and domains, it is only necessary to go to the tree view and "select and drag"  move the recently created sensor to the level that you want. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img025.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Add sensor</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>In the following images they show some examples of the sensors that can be added to the infrastructure (active in the Flow App) and the information that the system requests to create.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img026.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Add Flow sensor</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img027.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Add MSE sensor</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img027b.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Add Meraki sensor</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<important>
				<title>Important</title>
				<para>In the moment in which a redBorder sensor is created, by default it's set as the root, above the domain level.</para>
				<para>The user can organize its sensor infrastructure in any moment, dragging and dropping the sensor in the level they want to place it in.</para>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">The sensor automatically inherits the properties of the root domain</emphasis> (policies, operating mode, Snort variables, etc.).</para>
			</important>			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Edit a sensor: Flow</title>
			<para>The configuration and editing of Flow sensors is possible in two different ways: selecting <literal>View>Flow sensors</literal> or, through the setup icon found in the corresponding row to a Flow sensor in the tree view. </para>
			<para>In both cases, by selecting the settings option, the user accesses a screen where you can edit the following information (these fields vary depending on whether consulting a ASR, WLC, Flow, MSE, etc., sensor):</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img028.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Edit Flow sensor</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para>General: allows you to enter general configuration data of the sensor.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img029.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Edit Flow sensor: General</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Description</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>IP: indicate the IP of which the sensors come from.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Version</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Client DNS resolution: performs a reverse resolution from client name.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Target DNS resolution: performs a reverse lookup for the destination.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enable SPAN port: activate in the case that the flows from Flow derived from that sensor are associated with a Span port.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Active NSMP: this option appears in the case of WLC sensors. Through this protocol, redBorder is able to detect which access points are associated to each client and the health of the WLC controller. Activate the check of the desired option.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Active Radius: activate this option so that redBorder receive the information of Radius Accounting of the sensor. With this information platform can detect the user name associated with the client and the AP to which it is connected. </para>
					<para>It is very important that you enter the shared secret key with the sensor; otherwise there will be no communication between the Radius Accounting and sensor.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>SNMP: to activate the SNMP sensor, it's necessary that the user indicates the community it has to connect with.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img030.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Edit Flow sensor: SNMP</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>-Community</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Version:</para>
					<para>-1</para>
					<para>-2c</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Location: indicates the geographical location of the sensor.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Home Networks: add local networks of client for that sensor. This way redBorder can directly detect the traffic and IP that belongs to the client.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scale="30" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img031.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Edit Flow sensor: Home Networks</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img032.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Edit Flow sensor: Add new Home Networks</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>MAC Routers: works the same way as the <literal> Home Networks </literal> but in this case at level 2 or by MAC address. You can also add a new Router MAC.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch11_img033.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Edit Flow sensor: Add new Router MAC</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
