<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2019">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Eneo Tecnología S.L. |">
]>
<chapter>
	<title>redBorder web platform</title>
	<para>Once the Manager installation process has finished, the user can access the redBorder web platform in the address bar of their IP management browser assigned to the Manager.</para>
	<para><screen>https://IP-managerAddress</screen></para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch04_img001.png"/>
		</imageobject>
		<textobject>
			<phrase>Screen access to the redBorder platform: username and password</phrase>
		</textobject>
		<caption>
			<para>Screen access to the redBorder platform: username and password</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	<note>
		<title>Nota</title>
		<para>You can login to the platform using the account indicated by default: <emphasis role="bold">admin or admin@redborder.net</emphasis> and the password that has been inserted in the Manager installation process.</para>
	</note>
	<warning>
	<title>Warning</title>
		<para>The web management will not work if you try to access it through a web that isn't encrypted.</para>
	</warning>
	<para>As soon as you've accessed the redBorder platform, the first thing you'll see is a <emphasis role="bold">dashboard</emphasis> where you will find different metrics and data about the status of sensors, domains, etc.</para>
	<para>This home screen is fully customizable. The user will be able to create as many dashboards per profile as deemed necessary.<footnote><para>In the case of the Community version, the number of customizable dashboards is limited to one per user profile.</para></footnote></para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450"  fileref="images/ch04_img002.png"/>
		</imageobject>
		<textobject>
			<phrase>Home screen administrator of the Manager: dashboard</phrase>
		</textobject>
		<caption>
			<para>Home screen administrator of the Manager: dashboard</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	<section>
		<title>Interface structure of the redBorder platform</title>
		<para>There is a structure that is repeated for all interfaces in the redBorder web platform. Knowing these features will help navigate the web in a convenient and easy way. <footnote><para>The attached image corresponds to a redBorder installation with the active Apps of Flow, IPS and Malware. The structure will be the same for any redBorder installation that is performed, depending only on which Apps are available in the top menu bar, and whether or not they are activated.</para></footnote></para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Menu bar:</emphasis> here you will find direct access to all sections of the redBorder platform. It is subdivided into two different areas according to operability:</para>
				<para><emphasis>a) Analytical area (top left margin):</emphasis> in this area you will find all the data collected by the sensors shown in different metrics and reports.</para>
				<para><emphasis>b) Configuration area (top right margin):</emphasis> configuration options and management of the Apps and redBorder platform.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Submenu:</emphasis> shows the available options according to the section you are consulting.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Main area:</emphasis> this is the content section. In this area the data is shown in different metrics and graphs that are completely customizable. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Summary:</emphasis> below the graph you will find a summary of the information shown in the metric, providing the total values.</para><!--review-->
			</listitem>	
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Search engine:</emphasis> allows to quickly search any feature in the data table with the attribute that is being consulted. You only have to enter the IP, sensor, client, etc. that you want to consult. In addition, the searches can become filters as we will see further ahead.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Data table:</emphasis> provides details of the information displayed in the metric. Furthermore, they can perform different actions by rows. These actions depend on the tab/App we are consulting.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<section>
			<title>Included options in the menu bar</title>
			<para>Let's do a quick overview of the options that can be found in the menu bar, in the area of analysis and configuration. In later sections functionality and configuration of these options will be analyzed.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch04_img003.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Options included in the menu bar</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Option details included in the menu bar</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis>Dashboard:</emphasis> Provides a summary of the events received by the sensors, displaying them in different metrics. This is the screen shown by default when you log into the redBorder platform.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch04_img002.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Dashboard</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Dashboard</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis>Events/sensors:</emphasis> Next, the user will see the events in which the sensors registered in the Manager. In the attached screenshot: Flow, IPS and Malware.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch04_img005.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Sensors: view of flow events</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Sensors: view of Flow events</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis>Monitor:</emphasis> in this sections they show the status of the cluster in data and graphics, hardware and system, as well as the network and other statistics collected by the sensors.</para> 
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch04_img006.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Monitor: Manager state of health</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Monitor: Manager state of health</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis>Social:</emphasis> shows a summary of the users' activity maintained in a selected area with social networks (Twitter and Instagram).</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch04_img007.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Network user interaction with Social Media</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Network user interaction with Social Media</para>		
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis>Reports:</emphasis> In this section the user will be able to see a list of all stored reports, import and export reports and create new customizable reports thanks to the widgets.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch04_img008.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Reports</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Reports</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Configuration area</emphasis></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch04_img009.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Menu bar detail: configuration area</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Menu bar detail: configuration area</para>
				</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para><emphasis>Search engine:</emphasis> facilitates locating elements/values of the platform according to the search engine term entered by the user.</para>
				<para><emphasis>Sensors:</emphasis> Displays a list of the added sensors and the organization tree. It also contains global and local policies defined for each domain.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch04_img010.png"/>
					</imageobject>	
					<textobject>
						<phrase>List of sensors</phrase>
					</textobject>
					<caption>
						<para>List of sensors</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para><emphasis>Tools:</emphasis> Provides a list of the configuration options that are available to the administrator profile and in read mode for the rest of the users.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="450" fileref="images/ch04_img011.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>Available options in Tools</phrase>
					</textobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Available options in Tools</para>
				</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para><emphasis>Administrator:</emphasis> this section shows a list of notifications, as well as the different options available for managing users, contextual help of the platform and the safe disconnect button: <literal>Logout.</literal></para>	
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch04_img012.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Available options in Administrator</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para><emphasis>Show Help:</emphasis> Enabling this option will activate a pop-up window providing help during the Manager administrator navigation. It is identified with a question mark.</para>
				<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scale="60" align="center" fileref="images/ch04_img013.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>Help activation</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Help activation</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>	
</chapter>
