<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2015">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Eneo Tecnología S.L. |">
]>
<chapter>
	<title>What is redBorder?</title> <!--Capítulos 1 y 2 incluyen malware-->
	<para><emphasis role = "bold"> redBorder horama </emphasis> is a unified security monitoring platform, combining the possibilities offered by the total network visibility thanks to the App, redBorder Flow, together with network security control by redBorder IPS and malware protection systems. </para>
	<para><emphasis role = "bold"> sensors </emphasis> Linux systems with a distribution fully focused on the acquisition  and / or intrusions in the segments of the network where they are located or, in the detection of any abnormality or variation in the flow of your network. </para>
	<blockquote><para> "Its new Big Data backend inaugurates a new era in the management of events using Open Source technology, through a combination of Hadoop for mass storage (Raw) with an OLAP engine to slice and dice data for analysis. In addition, it channels Real-time events for enrichment, correlation and data mining." </para></blockquote>
	<para>redBorder offers a fully scalable ecosystem and Cloud-ready to support the largest deployments.</para> 
	<section>
		<title>Basic scenario for installing redBorder Horama</title>
		<para>A typical basic scenario proposed for the solution consists of a set of sensors arranged in different sensitive points of the organizational network that will connect with a manager or managers to cluster management and monitoring.</para>
		<para>These points are formed by network links, called segments, which will circulate sensitive traffic and the sensor will analyze in a more or less transparent way, depending on the mode set operation (IPS / IDS).</para>
		<para>For the planning of the installation of sensor equipment, you should consider some fundamental aspects:</para> 
		<itemizedlist mark="circle">
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">The bypass segments</emphasis> The bypass segments (specific network interfaces paired, usually with support bypass) will be lodged in traffic to analyze.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Management interfaces</emphasis> (in the form of bonding) for remote access for both normal systems as well as from the Manager. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">The IPMI access interfaces for remote management of hardware</emphasis> (SOL connection or Serial Over Lan, iKVM and ipmi command as start, restart and shutdown).</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>For the <emphasis role="bold">Manager,</emphasis> a specific hardware will not be necessary. The only condition is <emphasis role="bold">the existence of one or more network interfaces.</emphasis></para>
		<para> In this way it allows the creation of a bonding for the management and connection of with sensors and other bonding (optional) for their communications to other networks. Both systems support the standard 802.1q virtual LAN (optional when set).</para>
		<warning>
			<title>Warning</title>
			<para>It is VERY IMPORTANT that the Manager configuration is done first (or manager clusters) before configuring the sensors.</para>
			<para>The Manager must be operational and in a network accessible to the sensors.Some of the sensor configuration processes depend on the access to Manager.<footnote><para>The redBorder Manager installation scenario is the same regardless of the sensors to be installed and registered in the Manager (IPS, Flow, Malware (beta) or Vault (beta).</para></footnote>.</para>
		</warning>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch01_img001.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
					<phrase>Basic scenario for installing the Manager</phrase>
				</textobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Basic scenario for installing the Manager</para>
				</caption>
		</mediaobject>		    
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Installation Requirements of redBorder Manager</title>
		<para>redBorder manager can be installed by two Possible infrastructure:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Physical machine:</emphasis> local disk of your computer (Hardware).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">VM:</emphasis> virtualization and cloud structure.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<important>
			<title>Important</title>
			<para>Installation Requirements for redBorder Manager on a physical computer:</para>
			<para>Memory and storage.<emphasis role= "bold"> 100GB hard drive and a minimum of 16GB of RAM </emphasis>.(This figure depends on the number of sensors assigned, OS images assigned and the size of them).</para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Two network interfaces</emphasis> for operating the Manager.</para>
		</important>
		<note>
			<title><emphasis role="bold">Compatible Cloud Solutions:</emphasis></title>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para>VMWare</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open Stack</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Amazon Web Services (AWS)</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</note>
	</section>
</chapter>
