<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE preface PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2022">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Eneo Tecnología S.L. |">
]>
<preface id="pref-manual-Preface">
  <title>Preface</title>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="Common_Content/Conventions.xml"/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="Feedback.xml">
  </xi:include>
    <section>
		<title> Welcome to redBorder</title>
		<para>Thank you very much for downloading or purchasing version 3.1 of redBorder.</para>
		<para>This manual is intended for users who have the <emphasis role="bold">Enterprise</emphasis> version, release 3.1.XX-X.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Knowing the Official Manager Installation Guide</title>
			<para>This guide contains very useful information that will help you accurately perform the installation of redBorder Manager.</para>
			<para>It explains in detail how to navigate through the Manager Installation Wizard and is just as valid if you got a DVD installation as if performed the download directly from the ISO. Thanks to the configuration wizard you can configure the manager. </para>
			<para>his document is just as ideal for users who want to replace the the old version, as it is for those who are installing redBorder version 3 for the first time. </para>
			<para>If you’re an experienced user and have already performed the installation of redBorder on other occasions, you can skip directly to chapter 3, in which you learn how to move in redBorder web platform.</para>
		</section>
    </section>
    <section>
		<title>Requirements for the implementation of redBorder</title>
		<para>The redBorder platform can be installed through 2 possible infrastructures:</para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Physical machine: </emphasis> local drive of your computer (Hardware). </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Virtual machine:</emphasis> structure of virtualization or Cloud.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<important>
			<title>Important</title>
			<para>Requirements for the installation of redBorder Manager from a physical computer: </para>
			<para>Memory and Storage: <emphasis role= "bold"> 60GB for hard drive and a minimum of 16GB of RAM. However 32GB of RAM recommended. </emphasis>(This figure depends on the number of sensors assigned).</para>
			<para>In the case that a <emphasis role="bold">cluster</emphasis> has been created, two network interfaces are necessary: One for network management (Management IP Address) and one for network synchronization (Sync IP address): If you have created a cluster two network interfaces are required.</para>
		</important>
		<note>
			<title><emphasis role="bold">Cloud Compatible Solutions</emphasis></title>
			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
				<listitem>
					<para>VMWare</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open Stack</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Amazon Web Services (AWS)</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</note>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Versions of redBorder Manager software </title>
		<para>This document addresses the installation of the redBorder Manager that includes the following software versions: </para>
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para>Apache Zookeeper 3.4.6</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Apache Kafka 0.10.0.1</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>druid 0.12.3</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>logstash 7.4.2</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>postgreSQL 9.2.10</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>chef 11.14.6</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>nginx 1.6.2</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>keepalived 2.0.18</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
</preface>
